## **Jeff Dickinson**

# 2101 Liberty Lane, Papillion, NE 68133

jeffdickinson@yahoo.com, 402-319-9380

#### **SUMMARY:**

Jeff Dickinson is a Senior Project Manager and Programmer with more than 20 years of experience in SAS programming and analytical consulting in the pharmaceutical and biotechnology industries. Recently has been working on open-source projects for pharmaceutical analysis data in R. He has specialized in pharmaceutical clinical reporting and is an expert in the areas of efficacy and safety reporting, CDISC ADaM dataset programming and QC, response analysis, survival analysis, biostatistical programming and pharmacokinetics (PK). He has worked extensively in R and SAS.

### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:**

DataCeutics, Inc.

2005 - present

## **Senior Project Manager**

Project Manager for a PK team of programmers; Project Manager for QC team; developer of macros for standardized PK dataset programming process; developer of standardized QC macros for CDISC ADaM-like datasets including response and time to event; developer and QC programmer for NONMEM and Exposure Response analysis; developer of PKS analysis-ready datasets and PK concentration tables, listing and graphs; QC programming team lead for global series of clinical studies utilizing CDISC data standards (SDTM and ADaM); QC programming team lead for laboratory dataset programming; QC programming (datasets, tables, listings, and graphs) for major clinical studies; clinical data programming for tables, listings and graphs, including survival analysis and forest plots; creation and verification programming of patient profiles for an NDA submission; technical SAS programming and project management of clinical programming teams.

PPD 2004 - 2005

#### **SAS Programmer**

Provided SAS programming services to medical device division of major CRO; programmed tables and listings for clinical study reports; responsible for the verification of programs for NDA submission; acted as lead programmer on several projects, coordinating the programming activities of other programmers.

Peabus Consulting, LLC

2003 - 2004

## Statistical Programming

Provided biostatistical programming services to clients in the pharmaceutical industry; created and verified the programming of patient profiles for a major pharmaceutical company for an NDA submission. Designed and delivered training on "Good Statistical Programming Practice" for pharmaceutical company.

3M Pharmaceuticals

2002 - 2003

## **Supervisor, Statistical Programming**

Established new statistical programming group for 3M Pharmaceuticals; conducted national and regional search to fill six simultaneous openings for statistical programmers; wrote new Work

Practice Guidelines for SAS programming; led Six Sigma Green Belt team on data edit programming; planned strategy for electronic submission. Implemented standard submission dataset structures (CDISC); worked out technical specifications on assembling datasets and data definition files for electronic submission.

AstraZeneca 1998 – 2001

## **Senior Manager, Statistical Programming**

Managed programming teams for Respiratory Therapeutic Area (TA) and Experimental Medicine; coordinated programming activities for numerous clinical studies and planned NDA; ensured quality and timeliness of programming deliverables for Respiratory TA. Integrated programming processes for Respiratory TA after merger; implemented a standardized set of macros for reporting for Respiratory TA; worked globally for standardization of data reporting; reviewed clinical study reports, protocols, statistical analysis plans, case report forms and database specifications for Respiratory TA; completed performance evaluations for direct reports. Participated in Electronic Records/Electronic Signatures remediation project; provided statistical programming support as needed for Respiratory TA; generated analysis datasets, tables, listings, and graphs for clinical trial reporting in Respiratory and Clinical Pharmacology areas; worked as part of team to devise new set of standards for data reporting in Respiratory area; rewrote several major analysis programs for Respiratory Therapeutic Area. Wrote numerous small utility programs (macro-based) to increase programming efficiency and assist other programmers with common tasks.

### **EDUCATION:**

Ph.D. Zoology, Michigan State University, East Lansing, MI, 1997
M.A. Psychology, University of Toronto, Toronto, Canada, 1991
B.A. Psychology, Carleton College, Northfield, MN, 1990
Postdoctoral Fellow, Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory, Cold Spring Harbor, NY, 1997–1998
Assistant Research Scientist, Department of Biology, New York University, New York, NY, 1996–1997
Graduate Assistant, Michigan State University, East Lansing, MI, 1991–1996
Teaching Assistant, University of Toronto, Toronto, Canada, 1990–1991

## **SKILLS:**

- R
- SAS
- RECIST analysis
- PK programming
- Macro programming

- CDISC SDTM and ADaM
- Forest Plots
- Survival Analysis
- QC Programming
- Project Management

### **CLINICAL DATA STANDARDS EDUCATION:**

CDISC Programming Standards Part 1/DataCeutics, Inc., 2011 CDISC Programming Standards Part 2/DataCeutics, Inc., 2011